# Cheng-Yu Chuang

San Francisco, CA • chengyualantw@gmail.com • (415) 405-6593

LinkedIn: <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/cy-alan-chuang/">www.linkedin.com/in/cy-alan-chuang/</a> Profile: <a href="mailto:cheng-yu-alan.github.io/">cheng-yu-alan.github.io/</a>

## **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with a master's degree in Computer Science and 5 years of industry experience transforming business requirements and functional specifications into software solutions and improving efficiency, scalability, and stability of various system resources. Experienced with Microservice, Spring Boot, and Kafka. Demonstrates proficiency in Java and Python, with strong system design skills on the backend. Adept at keeping pace with evolving Machine Learning technology.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Self-Employed

2023-09 - PRESENT

Developing Smart Gym System at Strength Camp SF, integrating AI capabilities to generate customized workout/diet
plans autonomously and offering personalized suggestions for members – Python, Java, Spring Boot, REST API, Fast API,
AWS Lambda, InfluxDB, Telegraf, Grafana, Kafka, Eureka, Hystrix, MongoDB, Docker

# Research Assistant | SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY

2021-12 - 2023-9

- Created a website utilizing deep learning techniques to assist blind and visually impaired communities in accessing videos
   Java, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Python, PyTorch, MySQL, REST API, JSON, Docker, Linux
- Accomplished research work by improving video description AI model to be state-of-the-art model, resulting in an average 2.58% increase in all scores - <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04480">https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.04480</a>

## Senior Software Engineer | TRADEBEYOND (FORMERLY CBX SOFTWARE)

2019-09 - 2020-11

- Developed supply chain systems with over 30,000 retail & supplier partners, and 50,000 users in more than 50 countries –
  Java, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, REST API, JSON, Gitlab, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm,
  Linux, Azure, AWS S3, HTTP, Eureka, Kafka, Hystrix, Microservice
- Promoted to Senior Software Engineer based on extraordinary performance and team collaboration within 6 months
- Implemented Netflix Eureka as service discovery and Kafka as message broker to decouple back-end services
- Integrated Sonar Qube into development workflow, eliminating over 100 potential bugs and elevating code quality through automated code reviews that efficiently identify and rectify bugs
- Delivered multiple cross-team presentations on cutting-edge technologies.
- Introduced JUnit and Mockito into development process to enhance code quality
- Implemented JMeter integration within CI/CD pipeline, enabling automated stress testing as an integral part of deployment process
- Managed development timeline using Jira and Agile methodologies, ensuring efficient project planning and execution

#### Software Engineer | HUNG YANG SOFTWARE

2017-08 - 2019-07

- Maintained an ERP system for Far EasTone, third-largest telecommunications company in Taiwan Java, JavaScript,
  JSP, Oracle SQL, Tomcat, Linux, SVN
- Reduced 30% development and maintenance effort and 15% CPU and RAM usage by developing a new system
- Rated top performer in the department twice among 120 Software Engineers (2018 & 2019)

### Software Engineer | LEADTEK RESEARCH

2015-09 - 2017-06

- Developed 2 Android healthcare applications assisting users in tracking and recording health data Java, Android, SQLite
- Created a kiosk system for over 20 hospitals to help patients record health data Java, Android, SQLite, SOAP

#### **EDUCATION**

M.S. in Computer Science | SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY | 4.0 GPA

2021-2023

B.E. in Computer Science and Information Engineering | NATIONAL CENTRAL UNIVERSITY

2010-2014

# **SKILL**

Languages: Java, Python, C, C++, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, JSON, YAML, Protobuf

Database: SQL (Oracle SQL, MySQL, SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB, Elasticsearch), TSDB (InfluxDB)

Frameworks: Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Android, JUnit, Mockito, REST API, Fast API, Hystrix

Developer Tools: Azure, AWS, Git, SVN, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, JMeter, Jenkins, VS Code, Kafka, Eureka, Grafana